Hello friends, welcome to Tippon Sites.
In today's video, we will talk
about eyes. Whether eye treatment is
covered by our health card
or not, or what all
things are covered, I am going to
tell you all about it in detail in today's video.
I was getting a lot of questions
through comments, Sir, please
make a video on what things are covered in the eyes,
or which surgeries are covered,
or whether we can also go to the OPD and get our treatment done through
our health card or our
health policy. I am going to answer all those questions
in this video. So, please stay tuned till the
end of the video. If
you are new to the channel, then subscribe to the channel and
press the bell icon so that
you keep getting notifications of new videos. So
let's start the video
[Music].
First of all, you should know
that whenever you purchase a health insurance
policy, or you
get a corporate or group policy, when can we use it
and what all things are covered under it.
Regarding eyes,  If we
come to this then the basic thing is that first of all we should
know that our card will be valid
only in case of admission. If it is an
individual policy i.e. any
policy taken by ourselves, then we
take a separate plan in it related to OPD. OPD
related means that if we have to visit a
doctor in OPD and
we have to cover that expense also under our policy,
then for that we have to take a separate plan.
If we use any card on a regular basis, then
for that we will have to be
admitted for a minimum period. If
we use any card on a regular basis in the
hospital, then normally we will have to stay for at least 24 hours
or if there is a minor
surgery of seven to eight hours or any
minor procedure, that too is covered. That condition will have to be
seen whether those
things
are covered or not according to the terms and conditions of your policy. So the same things apply during eye
operation or eye treatment
also. So
what happens in eye treatment, whenever we
go to a doctor, normally we  There is
some problem like low vision
or not being able to see far or near
or if you can see near but not far
or there is blurred vision or dizziness
or headache.
We face these types of problems for which there is no
surgery or operation
or there is no other treatment
for which you need to be
admitted in the hospital. In that condition, if
OPD treatment is covered in your policy, that is, the
OPD expenses
are covered in your policy and you have taken such a personal
plan, then that expense can be covered
because during all these treatments,
what the doctor does is check your eyes,
gives you some drops to put in
or after eye testing,
advises you to get glasses made.
Glasses are also a non-payable item which is
not covered. No insurance company
covers its cost. You have to get it
made at your own end and pay for it. The
insurance
company does not pass any claim for this. So,
all this OPD  The basic treatment is done which will
not be covered in your health card
if you have taken any plan related to OPD.
Now you must be thinking that
we have problems mostly in our eyes, that is why
we
purchased a health insurance policy so that our
expenses would be covered under it.
But there are some terms and conditions in it,
when you have a lot of pain in your eyes
and the doctor advises that you
need surgery. There are different
types of eye surgeries, so the
cost of those surgeries is covered. I am
telling you the names of some of those surgeries
which can be covered in your health insurance card.
For that also you will have to
take pre-approval because the
policies of all the insurance companies are
different, so you have to check that
and also talk to your customer care.
But mostly, the
surgery which I am going to tell you in the policies,
this surgery is covered, you
can easily go and get it done. Some names are of this type, the
most important surgery which is done inside the eyes
and normally most of the people  There is also
this problem, it is called
cataract surgery. In English, it is
called cataract surgery. This surgery is
covered under your health insurance policy. The
second is LASIK surgery. The third is
glaucoma surgery. I am
telling you the name of this third surgery. The fourth surgery is
corneal transplant. This is also a surgery.
You can get it covered under your health card through
your claim. The
fifth is retinal surgery. There are
810 types of surgeries in this type, which are
covered under your policy. You
can get your pre-approval for it and
can easily use your health card. The
insurance company will cover whatever your expenses are. So, this type
of surgery is covered under your health insurance policy.
You should
also confirm this by talking to your customer care.
Or I will tell you the easiest way,
that you should get pre-
approval before getting any surgery done
so that you can be assured whether
your surgery will be covered under your health card
or not.
These things are covered by pre-approval.  You will get to know in advance about pre-
approval. I have already made a video
about how the process of pre-approval is done and
what documents
you people need. So in today's
video, I told you how
you can find out
what eye treatments are covered under your policy, that is,
which treatments you can take under it.
I have told you the complete process in detail. Still, if you have
any questions regarding this video,
you can write to me in the comment section and
I will answer you.
Apart from this, if you have any query regarding your health insurance claim, then
you must ask me questions related to that query.
You will
definitely get the answer to that too in limited time. So that's all for today's video. See you
in the next video, till then,
goodbye.